<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Khaled2049&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://khaled2049.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Khaled2049&#39;s Blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Khaled2049&#39;s Blog</title>
      <url>https://khaled2049.github.io/images/papermod-cover.png</url>
      <link>https://khaled2049.github.io/images/papermod-cover.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.125.7</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 12:29:43 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://khaled2049.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to do an AWS blue green deployment without downtime</title>
      <link>https://khaled2049.github.io/posts/blue-green-deployment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 12:29:43 -0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://khaled2049.github.io/posts/blue-green-deployment/</guid>
      <description>AWS RDS Blue-Green Deployment for Major Version Upgrade One of my first key tasks in my new role was upgrading our AWS RDS cluster from PostgreSQL 14 to 16. When dealing with database upgrades, I always lean toward a cautious approach to minimize risk. Our cluster was running on version 14, and a major version upgrade was required to bring it up to 16.
In this blog, I’ll walk you through the steps I took to complete this upgrade with minimal risk and zero downtime.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Sync Investor Update Two</title>
      <link>https://khaled2049.github.io/posts/novel-sync-investor-update-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 20:29:30 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://khaled2049.github.io/posts/novel-sync-investor-update-two/</guid>
      <description>State of Novel Sync as of 2/17/2025 Okay, so I know haven&amp;rsquo;t been giving plenty of updates here, and I honestly have no excuses. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on novel-sync and adding features left and right. There’s still a lot to improve and polish, but by the end of this year, I expect this project to be pretty solid. My current goal is simply to keep enhancing it. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve added all the main features, I&amp;rsquo;ll focus on polishing it and writing about what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Goals</title>
      <link>https://khaled2049.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 22:07:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://khaled2049.github.io/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>2025 is here, and it’s shaping up to be the year of big, bold moves. There’s one goal I’ve set that stands above everything else on my list: starting a startup.
Over the years, I’ve toyed with ideas, side projects, and what-ifs. But there’s something about 2025 that feels different. This is the year to turn thoughts into action and ambition into reality. Starting a startup isn’t just about building a product or a service; it’s about building a life on my own terms, driven by passion, curiosity, and a desire to solve real-world problems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Novel Sync</title>
      <link>https://khaled2049.github.io/posts/novel-sync-investor-update/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 11:06:16 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://khaled2049.github.io/posts/novel-sync-investor-update/</guid>
      <description>I love reading books, and I&amp;rsquo;ve always wanted to create a startup. We’re often encouraged to follow our passions and spend time doing what we enjoy, so I decided to combine the two things I love. That’s how my journey with NovelSync began.
I’m not expecting to make money from this project, and that’s perfectly fine. My goal is to create a space where others can come together to read, write and share stories.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
